I am graduate (B.Sc.) with 5 years of experience in **BPO industry**. Have proven track record of **Team development, people management, process management; process transitioning, process improvement and project management**. I want to place myself in more challenging role in service industry to utilize my relevant experience for carrier enhancement while contributing best to business goals.

### **Educational Qualification**

- Earned INTRO 320 certificate in US P&C Insurance from ACPCU through Axis Insurance Academy in 2010
- Completed B.Sc. (PCM) in 2005 from Agra University
- Completed Intermediate education with science stream in 2001 from CBSE.
- Completed High School education with science stream in 1999 from CBSE

## **PROJECTS**

- Migration of 54 FTEs worth of work from US from September 2009 to December 2011 It was an umbrella project consists of 5 sub-projects. I have been a part of these project series in the role of Assistant Manager and SME; while working onsite and offsite both. Out of 54, 30 FTEs worth of work was transitioned in the capacity of Assistant Manager and initial 24 FTEs were transitioned in the capacity of SME. Following were the key responsibilities assigned to me in these series of projects
  - Working with onshore team in identifying the opportunities of work that can be transitioned offshore
  - Assisting Migration Manager in preparing scope and plan for the project
  - o Acquiring, Developing and Managing project team
  - Active Involvement in service level agreement discussions and negotiations
  - Active Involvement in trainings with Knowledge Transfer resources
  - Monitoring the project at execution level for timeliness and quality
  - Proactively communicating project progress to internal and external stakeholders
  - Working with internal stakeholders in managing expectations of the clients progressively during the project
  - Documentation of statement of work at contract level as well as for processing level
- Task Grouping This project was undertaken to put all the tasks in process in logical sequence of flow and groups some of the tasks depending on the nature of tasks. Before this project process had ~140 different tasks types. Post detailed study of all these were grouped in 83 tasks types. Following were the key benefits delivered by this project
  - More meaningful structure to the process end to end with clear flow of transactions defining upstream and downstream
  - Streamlining of transactions helped in planning of forwarding seeding of the resources
  - o Faster turnaround time for some of the transactions
  - o Lessor average handling time by merging transactions
  - o Improvement in MEI resulting bottom line benefits of ~ \$50, 000 annually
  - Improvement in knowledge retention

- Improvement in process accuracy
- Escalation Reduction I have been a part of escalation reduction project with Black Belt. This project involved identification of steps in end to end process that were being handled onshore and were causing escalations in downstream transactions, and getting offshore team trained on those steps to release resources onshore. Following are some of the key benefits delivered through this project
  - $\circ$   $\,$  Improvement in topline benefits of  $\sim$  \$20, 000 annually by getting more work offshored
  - o Improvement in client satisfaction score
  - Lessor dependency of onshore team
- Cross Training Structure This project was undertaken to set up the structure for cross
  training in the process. Objective was to define criticality of the task types and skill set of
  the people, cross train people on the tasks as per skills and criticality of the tasks. Criticality of the tasks is a factor of required skill set and volume behavior of the tasks. Following
  are the benefits achieved out of this project
  - Criticalities of the tasks are defined and agreed with client; it helps in prioritizations if there are operations challenges in more than one areas
  - Skill set of the people are defined that helps in identifying the people when cross training are required. It also helps in performance evaluation of processors
  - o Great results in people engagement and development
  - Sufficient number of people are trained on each tasks types to manage any spike in volumes or manage operations in case of unplanned absenteeism

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Assistant Manager with Infosys BPO
– Aug 2012 till date

Currently working with Infosys BPO, as an Assistant Manager for one of the US property and casualty insurance client. Following are the responsibilities of my current role

- Responsible of handling of a team of 40, Associates, Sr. Associate and SMEs/Trainers
- Identifying and Planning for training opportunities of team for both soft skills and process knowledge
- O Administrative responsibilities of the team
- Planning and execution of team building and motivations activities for team engagement to achieve business objectives
- Ensuring attritions and absenteeism are within organizational norms
- Monitor, measure and report Team performance metrics
- Implement team incentive programs
- Ensuring timely and accurate turnaround of work received from onshore
- o Ensuring organizational and regulatory policies are adhered all the time
- Regular interactions with onshore Supervisors/ Stakeholders to manage client expectations

- Working with processors to identify process improvement opportunities and work upon those
- o Ensuring process documents are updated on regular basis
- Reporting process SLA scores to internal and external stakeholders on daily/weekly/monthly basis
- o Being a part of process reviews with onshore teams on weekly/monthly basis

## Assistant Manager with IBM Global Process Services (P) Ltd. – Aug 2010 till July 2012

Gained responsibilities of Assistant Manager while working with one of the US P&C insurance client, in Aug 2010 and travelled onshore to accomplish one of the largest migration projects in the process.

Following were the responsibilities this role

- Responsible of handling of a team of 35, Associates, Sr. Associate and SMEs/Trainers
- Working with migration manager to identify and work upon migration opportunities
- Identifying and Planning for training opportunities of team for both soft skills and process knowledge
- o Administrative responsibilities of the team
- Planning and execution of team building and motivations activities for team engagement to achieve business objectives
- Ensuring attritions and absenteeism are within organizational norms
- o Monitor, measure and report Team performance metrics
- o Implement team incentive programs
- Ensuring timely and accurate turnaround of work received from onshore
- o Ensuring organizational and regulatory policies are adhered all the time
- Regular interactions with onshore Supervisors/ Stakeholders to manage client expectations
- Working with processors to identify process improvement opportunities and work upon those
- o Ensuring process documents are updated on regular basis
- Reporting process SLA scores to internal and external stakeholders on daily/weekly/monthly basis
- o Being a part of process reviews with onshore teams on weekly/monthly basis

## Subject Matter Expert / Process Trainer with Axis Service.com (I) Pvt. Ltd. – Aug 2009 till July 2010

Gained responsibilities of Subject Matter Expert / Process Trainer.

Following were the responsibilities of my role

- Working as back up Assistant Manager to ensure timely accomplishment and reporting of SLAs
- Identifying training need opportunities in the team and conducting trainings according to those
- Getting trained on new tasks/processes from onshore team via Web Conferencing and imparting knowledge further to offshore team
- Updating processing documents as per new trainings / process updates
- Working as back up QCA

0

## Customer Care Executive with Wipro – June 2008 till Aug 2009

Joined Wipro as a Customer Care Executive and aligned to a US P&C Insurance client. Following were responsibilities of my role

- Processing different type of transactions / activities on insurance policies received from onshore team
- o Ensuring adherence of set policies/processes while achieving set individual targets
- o Acting as back up SME/QCA in absence of regular SME/QCA

#### **REWARDS AND RECOGNITIONS**

- Service Excellence Award in Assistant Manager category for year 2012
- Service Excellence Award in Assistant Manager category for year 2011
- Best SME of the process for Q4 of year 2010

#### WORKSHOPS / TRAININGS ATTENDED

- PMP Workshop (35 Contact Hours) from REP of PMI
- Operational Management from QAI
- Intro 320 in P&C Insurance from AICPCU
- Awareness of Six Sigma Elementary Training
- Lean Awareness
- Training on FIT (Fundamental of Insurance)
- TTT (Train the Trainer)
- Platform Skills Training
- Workshop on Thinking Ability
- Workshop on Customer Relationship Management

# **COMPUTER SKILLS**

• Operating Systems : Windows 2000/XP/7

MS Office Package : MS Word, MS Excel, MS PowerPoint, MS Vision,

MS Project, MS Outlook, MS OneNote